Which pets’ address is the finest in Paris
Which pets’ address is the finest in Paris
Which pets possess the longest pedigree
Which pets possess the longest pedigree
Which pets get to sleep on velvet mats
Which pets get to sleep on velvet mats
Naturellement The Aristocats
Naturellement The Aristocats
Which pets are blessed with the fairest forms and faces
Which pets are blessed with the fairest forms and faces
Which pets know best all the gentle social graces
Which pets know best all the gentle social graces
Which pets live on cream and loving pats
Which pets live on cream and loving pats
Naturellement The Aristocats
Naturellement The Aristocats
They show "aristocatic" bearing when they're seen upon an airing
They show "aristocatic" bearing when they're seen upon an airing
An "aristocatic" flair in what they do and what they say
An "aristocatic" flair in what they do and what they say
Aristocats are never found in alleyways
Aristocats are never found in alleyways
Or hanging 'round the garbage cans where common kitties play, oh, no
Or hanging 'round the garbage cans where common kitties play, oh, no
Which pets are known to never show their claws
Which pets are known to never show their claws
Which pets are prone to hardly any flaws
Which pets are prone to hardly any flaws
To which pets do the others tip their hats
To which pets do the others tip their hats
Naturellement The Aristocats
Naturellement The Aristocats
Marie, my little one...
...ماري، کوولوي من
you're going to be as beautiful as your mother.
.تو هم مثل مادرت خوشل ميشي
Isn't she, Duchess?
مه نه، دوشس؟
Careful, Toulouse!
!مواظب باش، تولوز
You're making it very difficult for Edgar.
.داري رانندي رو براي ادار سخت ميکني
Whoa, Frou-Frou, whoa. Steady, girl.
.وايسا، فرو فرو .وايسا، دختر
Thank you, Edgar.
.متشکرم، ادار
Oh, of course, Frou-Frou.
.اوه، البته، فرو فرو
I almost forgot.
.نزديک بود يادم بره
Madame, uh, uh, may I take your parcel, Madame?
مادام، مي خوايد بسته رو براتون بيارم، مادام؟
It really is much too heavy for you, Madame.
واقعا براي شما .خيلي سنينه، مادام
Now, tut tut, Edgar. Don't fuss over me.
.دست بردار، ادار .از من ايراد نير
Berlioz, come back here. Haven't you forgotten something, darling?
.برليوز، بررد اينجا يزي رو فراموش نکردي، عزيزم؟
Thank you, Miss Frou-Frou, for letting me ride on your back.
خانم فرو فرو، متشکرم که ذاشتين .شت شما سواري کنم
- You're quite welcome, young man. - How was that, Mama?
.اصلا قابلي نداشت، مرد جوان - طور بود، مامان؟ -
Very good, darling. That was very nice.
.خيلي خوب بود، عزيزم .خيلي خوب بود
Come along, Duchess, kittens. Come along.
.بياين تو، دوشس، به ربه ها .بياين تو
Oh, and Edgar, I'm expecting my attorney, Georges Hautecourt.
اوه، و ادار، من منتظر وکيلم .جورج هتکورت هستم
You remember him, of course.
.حتما اونو يادت مياد
Of course, Madame.
.البته، مادام
How could anyone forget him?
طور ممکنه کسي اونو فراموش کنه؟
Oh!
!اوه
Whoops! Oh, ho, ho. I'm not as spry as I was when I was 80. Eh?
اي داد! اوهو. مثل زماني که 80سالم بود زرن نيستم، نه؟
Ah, good day, sir. Madame is expecting you, sir.
.آه، روز خوش، آقا .مادام منتظر شماست، آقا
Evening! Evening, Edgar.
!عصر بخير .عصر بخير، ادار
Oh, another ringer, sir. You never miss.
.اوه، بازم زدين به هدف، آقا .هرز خطا نمي کنيد
Come on, Edgar. The last one up the stairs is a nincompoop.
بجنب، ادار. هر کس ديرتر .بالاي له ها برسه احمقه
Uh, uh, could we take the elevator this time, sir?
طوره اين دفعه از آسانسور استفاده کنيم، آقا؟
Oh, oh, that birdcage? Poppycock!
اوه، اون قفس رنده؟ !مزخرفه
Elevators are for old people. Whoops!
.آسانسور براي يرمردهاست !اي واي
Uh, may I give you a hand, sir?
اه، مي خوايد کمکتون کنم، آقا؟
You haven't got an extra foot, have you, Edgar?
تو که اي اضافي نداري، ادار، نه؟
That always makes me laugh, sir. Yes. Ha, ha. Every time.
.هميشه منو مي خندونين، آقا .آره. ها، ها. هميشه
- Whoa, ah! Let go of my cane! - Ooh, ah, careful, sir.
!آه! عصام رو ول کن - .اوه، مواظب باشيد، آقا -
Oh, please. l-l-I'm frightfully sorry, sir.
.اوه، خواهش ميکنم .واقعا متأسفم، آقا
Don't panic, Edgar.
.نترس، ادار
Upward and onward. Whee!
.بالا و جلو !هي
Am I going too fast for you, Edgar?
خيلي دارم سريع تر از تو ميرم، ادار؟
Oh, please, sir, hold...
...اوه، خواهش ميکنم، آقا، خودتون رو نه دارين
There now, Duchess. That's better.
.خيلي خب، دوشس .حالا بهتر شد
We must both look our best for Georges.
هر دومون براي جورج بايد .خوب به ظاهرمون برسيم
He's our oldest and dearest friend, you know.
اون قديمي ترين و عزيزترين .دوست ماست، مي دوني که
Come in.
.بيا تو
Announcing Monsieur...
...موسيو جورج هتکورت
Oh, my goodness, Edgar, I know Georges.
،اوه، خداي من، ادار .خودم جورج رو مي شناسم
Adelaide, my, my dear.
.آدلايد، عزيز من
So good to see you, Georges.
.خوشحالم مي بينمت، جورج
Ah, still the softest hands in all of Paris, eh?
آه، هنوز نرمترين دست در کل اريسه، ها؟
You're a shameless flatterer, Georges.
.جورج، اي الوس بي حيا
Adelaide, that's, that's music! It's from Carmen, isn't it?
!آدلايد، اين، صداي موسيقيه اثر کارمن هست، نه؟
That's right. It was my favorite role.
.درسته .نقش مورد علاقه من بود
Yes, yes!
!بله، بله
It was the night of your grand premiere that we first met, remember?
شب اجراي باشکوه شما بود که براي اولين بار همديه رو ديديم، يادته؟
- Oh, indeed, I do. - And how we celebrated your success.
.اوه، درسته - .و طور موفقيتت رو جشن رفتيم -
Champagne. Dancing the night away.
.شاماين .تمام شب رو رقصيديم
Oh, Georges!
!اوه، جورج
Oh.
.اوه
Oh, thank goodness.
.اوه، خدا رو شکر
Just in time.
.درست به موقع
Ah, Georges, we're just a pair of sentimental old fools.
آه، جرج، ما فقط يه جفت آدم .مسن ابله احساساتي هستيم
Now, Georges, do be serious.
.خب، جرج، شوخي کافيه
I've asked you to come here on a very important legal matter.
به خاطر يه مسأله حقوقي خيلي مهم .ازت خواستم بياي اينجا
Uh! Oh! Splendid, splendid!
!اِه! اوه !عاليه، عاليه
Who do you want me to sue, eh?
از کي مي خواي شکايت کني، ها؟
Oh, come now, Georges. I don't wish you to sue anyone.
.اوه، دست بردار، جرج .نمي خوام از کسي شکايت کنم
I simply want to make my will.
فقط مي خوام .وصيت نامه م تنظيم بشه
Will, eh? Will. Will.
وصيت نامه، ها؟ .وصيت. وصيت
Now then, who are the beneficiaries?
خب حالا، وارثين کيا هستن؟
Well, as you know, I have no living relatives...
،خب، مي دوني که ...من هي خويشاوند زنده اي ندارم
and naturally, I want my beloved cats to be always well cared for.
و طبيعتا، مي خوام هميشه از ربه هاي .محبوبم نهداري بشه
And certainly no one can do this better than my faithful servant, Edgar.
و مطمئنا هي کس نمي تونه اين کار رو .بهتر از مستخدم وفادارم، ادار انجام بده
Edgar?
ادار؟
Adelaide, you mean to say you're leaving your vast fortune to Edgar?
آدلايد، منظورت اينه که مي خواي ثروت عظيمت به ادار برسه؟
Everything you possess?
همه اموالت؟
Stocks and bonds? This, this mansion? Your country chateau?
موجودي و اوراق بهادار؟ اين، اين قصر؟ قصر ييلاقي؟
Art treasures? Jewels? And, and...
نجينه هاي هنري؟ جواهرات؟ ...و، و
Oh, no, no, Georges. To my cats.
.اوه، نه، نه، جرج .به ربه هام
- To your cats? - Cats!
به ربه هات؟ - !ربه ها -
Yes, Georges, I simply wish to have the cats inherit first.
بله، جرج، مي خوام در ابتدا .ربه هام وارث من باشن
Then, at the end of their life span...
...بعد، با ايان عمرشون
my entire estate will revert to Edgar.
.همه دارايي هام ميرسه به ادار
Cats inherit first! And I come after the cats.
!اول ربه ها وارث باشن .و بعدش من وارث ميشم
l, me, after... No. It's, it's not fair! Oh!
.من، من، بعد از... نه !عادلانه نيست! اوه
I mean... Ooh! Each cat'll live about 12 years.
!منظورم اينه که... اوه .هر ربه 12 سال عمر ميکنه
I can't wait... And, and each cat has nine lives.
...نمي تونم صبر کنم .و، و هر ربه 9 تا جون داره
That's... Four times 12, and multiply by nine times.
،ميشه... ميشه هار تا 12 سال .ضربدر 9 بار
No, it's less than that. Well, anyway, it's much longer than I'd ever live.
،نه، کمتره. خب، به هر حال .خيلي بيشتر از عمر منه
I'll be gone.
.من ميرم
No. Oh, no. They'll be gone.
.نه. اوه، نه .اونا ميرن
I'll think of a way.
.يه نقشه اي مي کشم
Why, there are a million reasons why I should.
را، يک ميليون دليل .براي اين کارم هست
All of them dollars.
.تمام اون دلارها
Millions.
.ميليون ها دلار
Those cats have got to go!
!اون ربه ها بايد برن
- Wait for me. Wait for me. - Me first. Me first.
.صبر کن منم بيام. صبر کن - .اول من. اول من -
Why should you be first?
را تو بايد اول باشي؟
Because I'm a lady, that's why.
.براي اين که من يه خانمم
Ha-uh. You're not a lady.
.تو يه خانم نيستي
You're nothin' but a sister.
.فقط يه آبجي هستي
I'll show you if I'm a lady or not.
بهت نشون ميدم .خانم هستم يا نه
- You're tickling. - Get her, Berlioz, get her.
.داري غلغلکم ميدي - .بيرش، برليوز، بيرش -
Fight fair, Marie.
.عادلانه دعوا کن، ماري
Females never fight fair.
.زن ها هي وقت عادلانه دعوا نمي کنن
Ah! Now that hurt. Mama, Mama!
.آخ! دردم رفت !مامان، مامان
Marie, darling, Marie, you must stop that.
،ماري، عزيزم، ماري .نبايد اين کارو بکني
Th-This is really not ladylike. And, Berlioz...
.اين در شأن يه خانم نيست ...و، برليوز
but such behavior is most unbecoming to a lovely gentleman.
.نين رفتاري اصلا برازنده يه مرد محترم نيست
Well, she started it.
.خب، اون شروع کرد
Ladies do not start fights...
...خانم ها دعواها رو شروع نميکنن
but they can finish them.
.ولي مي تونن تمومش کنن
Berlioz, now don't be rude.
.برليوز، بي ادب نباش
We were just practicing biting and clawing.
فقط داشتيم از رفتن .و نجه زدن رو تمرين مي کرديم
Aristocats do not practice biting and clawing...
ربه هاي اشرافي از رفتن ...و نجه زدن و اين يزها رو
and things like that, that's just horrible.
،تمرين نمي کنن .اين کارها زشته
But someday we might meet a tough alley cat.
ولي ممکنه يه روز .تو ن يه ربه خيابوني بيافتيم
Now, that will do. It's time we concerned ourselves with self-improvement.
خب، ديه کافيه. وقتشه که .با خودسازي به خودمون برسيم
Now, you want to grow up to be lovely, charming ladies and gentlemen.
،شما بايد مثل خانم ها و آقايون محترم .و دوست داشتني بزر بشيد
Now, Toulouse you go and start on with your painting.
.خب، تولوز، برو و نقاشيت رو بکش
Yes, Mama.
.بله، مامان
Mama, may we watch Toulouse paint before we start our music lesson?
مامان، ميشه قبل از درس موسيقي نقاشي کردن تولوز رو ببينيم؟
- Please? - Well, yes, my love, but...
خواهش ميکنم؟ - ...خب، آره، عزيزم، ولي -
- Whoops. -you must be very quiet. - Uh-oh.
.بايد خيلي ساکت باشي
Yeah.
.آره
- It's Edgar. - Yeah, old pickle puss Edgar!
.اون اداره - !آره، ادار ير مغز سته اي -
Old pickle puss! Now, now, Berlioz.
!مغز سته اي .خيلي خب، برليوز
That is not kind.
.اين کار خوبي نيست
You know Edgar is so fond of all of us...
ميدوني که ادار ...با همه ما مهربونه
and takes very good care of us.
.و خوب ازمون مراقبت ميکنه
Oh, Edgar, you sly old fox.
،اوه، ادار .اي روباه مکار ير
Oops! Oh, dear.
.واي! اوه، عزيز من
A slip of the hand and it's off to dreamland.
يه لغزش دست کافي بود .تا برم به سرزمين خواب و خيال
I say, that's not at all bad. Slip of the hand, dreamland.
.راستي، بدک نشد .يه لغزش دست، سرزمين خواب و خيال
Now, let's leave Toulouse to his painting.
حالا، تولوز رو تنها بذارين .تا نقاشيش رو بکشه
Now, dear, you go to the piano. Now, run along, both of you. Go ahead.
.حالا، به ها، بريد سراغ يانو .يالا، بريد، هردوتون. زود باشيد
- Yes, Mama.
.بله، مامان -
It's time to practice your scales and your arpeggios.
وقتشه آواز "طبل تو .و ن تو" رو تمرين کنيد
Ouch!
!آخ
I'm ready, maestro.
.من آماده ام، استاد
Oh! Mama, he did it again.
،اوه! مامان .بازم اون کارو کرد
- Tattletale. - Now, Berlioz.
.خبرين - .خب، برليوز -
Now, please, darling, settle down...
،حالا، عزيزم، لطفا ...آروم بير
and play me your pretty little song.
و براي من اون آواز .خوشلت رو بزن
Yes, Mama.
.بله، مامان
Do, me, so Do, do, so, me, do
Do, me, so Do, do, so, me, do
Every truly cultured music student knows
Every truly cultured music student knows
You must learn your scales and your arpeggios
You must learn your scales and your arpeggios
Bring the music ringing from your chest and not your nose
Bring the music ringing from your chest and not your nose
While you sing your scales and your arpeggios
While you sing your scales and your arpeggios
If you're faithful to your daily practicing
If you're faithful to your daily practicing
You will find your progress is encouraging
You will find your progress is encouraging
Do, me, so, me, do, me, so, me Fa, la, so it goes
Do, me, so, me, do, me, so, me Fa, la, so it goes
When you do your scales and your arpeggios
When you do your scales and your arpeggios
Do, me, so, do...
Do, me, so, do...
Do, me, so Do, do, so, me, do
Do, me, so Do, do, so, me, do
Though at first it seems as though it doesn't show
Though at first it seems as though it doesn't show
Like a tree ability will bloom and grow
Like a tree ability will bloom and grow
If you're smart you'll learn by heart what every artist knows
If you're smart you'll learn by heart what every artist knows
You must sing your scales and your
You must sing your scales and your
Arpeggios
Arpeggios
Ah, good evening, my little ones.
،آه، عصر بخير .کوولوهاي عزيزم
Your favorite dish prepared in a very special way.
غذاي مورد علاقه تون رو .يه طور ويژه ساختم
It's creme de la creme a la Edgar.
.بهترين بهترين هاي ادار هست
Sleep well. l, I mean, eat, eat well, of course.
،خوب بخوابيد. منظورم اينه که .بخوريد، خوب بخوريد، البته
Good evening, Duchess. Hello, kittens.
.عصر بخير، دوشس .سلام، به ربه ها
- Hello, Roquefort! - Hi, Roquefort!
!سلام، راکفورت -
Uh, good evening Monsieur Roquefort.
آه، عصر بخير .موسيو راکفورت
Mmm. Something smells awfully good.
.هوم. يه بوي خيلي خوب مياد
Mmm, what is that appetizing smell?
هوم، اين بوي اشتها آور يه؟
It's creme de la creme a la Edgar.
.بهترين بهترين هاي اداره
Oh, won't you join us, Monsieur Roquefort?
،اوه، به ما ملحق ميشيد موسيو راکفورت؟
Well, yes. l, I mean, well, I don't mean to interrupt.
،خب، بله. منظورم اينه که، خب .نمي خوام مزاحمتون بشم
But... But it so happens that I have a cracker with me.
.اما... اما اتفاقا يه بيسکويت دارم
Come on, Roquefort, have some.
.بيا، راکفورد، بيا بخور
Oh, thank you. Don't mind if I do.
.اوه، متشکرم .ببخش اين کارو ميکنم
Just a few dunks.
.فقط يه کم خيسش کنم
Mmm. Ooh, very good.
.هوم. اوه، خيلي خوب بود
My compliments to the chef.
.دست آشزش درد نکنه
Mmm, this is yummy.
.هوم، اين خوشمزه ست
Mmm, delicious.
.هوم، لذيذه
Double delicious.
.دو برابر لذيذه
This calls for another cracker. I'll be right back.
.جون ميده براي يه بيسکويت ديه .الان برمي ردم
So that's...
...س اين
creme de la creme...
...بهترين بهترين هاي
a la Edgar.
.ادار هست
Lafayette. Hey, Lafayette.
.لافيت .هي، لافيت
- Lafayette! - Well, I'm right here.
!لافيت - .يه، من اينجام -
Listen. Wheels approachin'.
.وش کن .صداي نزديک شدن رخه
Oh, Napoleon, we done bit six tires today.
اوه، نالئون، امروز شش تا .تاير رو از رفتيم
Chased four motorcars and a bicycle and a scooter.
هار تا ماشين و يه دورخه .و يه روروک رو تعقيب کرديم
Hush your mouth!
!نيشت رو ببند
It's a motorcycle. Two cylinder.
.يه موتور سيکلته .دو سيلندره
Chain drive.
.زنجير رخ
One squeaky wheel, on the front, it sounds like.
،يه رخ جيغ جيغو .ظاهرا جلو هست
Now, you go for the tires, and I'll go right for the seat of the problem.
خب، تو برو ساغ تايرها، منم يه راست ميرم .سراغ صندلي مورد
How come you always grab the tender part for yourself?
را هميشه قسمت حساس رو به عهده خودت ميذاري؟
'Cause I outrank you, that's why.
.ون برتر از تو هستم
Now, stop beatin' your gums and sound the attack.
حالا، وزه ت رو ببند .و صداي حمله رو ارس کن
No, that's mess call.
.نه، اين که ارس اعلام غذاست
Made a mess of it, huh?
اشتباهي ارس کردم، ها؟
You can be replaced, you know.
.ميدوني، ممکنه عوضت کنم
Okay, let's charge.
.خيلي خب، حمله کنيم -
Wait a minute. I'm the leader!
.صبر کن ببينم !من رئيسم
I'm the one that says when we go.
اين منم که ميه .ه موقعي بريم
Here we go. Charge!
.حالا بريم !حمله
Nice doggie, nice doggie. Heel, roll over, play dead.
.س خوب، س خوب .رو اشنه ا، برخ، آروم باش
This sure beats runnin', Napoleon.
.حتما سريع تر از دويدنه، نالئون
- Step on the gas, Napoleon. - I got her wide open.
.تخت از برو، نالئون - .اونو توي ديد دارم -
Yeow!
!آخ
Oh! Oh, where am I?
اوه! اوه، من کجا هستم؟
I'm not at home at all.
.اصلا تو خونه نيستم
Children, where are you? Answer me.
به ها، کجايين؟ .جواب بدين
Berlioz, Toulouse, Marie, where are you?
،برلويز، تولوز، ماري کجا هستين؟
Here I am, Mama.
.من اينجام، مامان
Marie, darling. Ar-Are you all right?
.ماري، عزيزم حالت خوبه؟
Uh, I guess I had a nightmare and fell out of bed.
فکر کنم خواب ديدم .و از تختخواب افتادم
Now, Marie darling, n-now, now don't be frightened.
،ماري عزيزم .اصلا نترس
- Mama! Mama! - That's Berlioz!
!مامان! مامان - !اون برليوزه -
Over here, darling Berlioz. Here we are.
.بيا اينجا، برليوز عزيزم .ما اينجاييم
A-And don't worry. Everything is going to be all right.
.و نران نباش .همه يز مرتب ميشه
I'm comin', Mama.
.دارم ميام، مامان
Gee, I'm cold and I'm wet.
.سردمه و خيس شدم
Mama?
مامان؟
Mama!
!مامان
Oh, darling.
.اوه، عزيزم
That's only a little frog, my love.
،اون فقط يه قورباغه کوولوهه .عزيز من
But he had a mouth like a "hippolotamus."
ولي دهانش به بزري .يه "اسب آبي" بود
Oh, what's so funny?
اوه، به ي مي خندي؟
Now, now, darling... Darlings, now you just stay here...
،خيلي خب عزيزم...عزيزانم ...حالا همين جا بمونين
and I go and I look for Toulouse.
.تا من برم دنبال تولوز بردم
Toulouse! Toulouse, where are you?
!تولوز تولوز، کجايي؟
- Toulouse!
!تولوز -
- Hey.
.هي -
What's all the yellin' about, huh?
براي ي داد مي زنين، ها؟
Why didn't you answer?
را جواب ندادي؟
Mama, he's been here all the time.
.مامان، از همون اول اين تو بوده
Oh, thank goodness. Oh.
.اوه، خدا رو شکر
A-Are you all right?
حالت خوبه؟
I was having a funny dream.
.يه خواب بامزه ديدم
Edgar was in it.
.ادار هم توش بود
And we were all riding and bouncing along...
و با اون داشتيم ...حرکت مي کرديم و
Frogs? Uh-oh, it wasn't a dream. Edgar did this to us.
.قورباغه ها؟ واي، خواب نبوده .ادار اين کارو با ما کرد
Edgar?
ادار؟
Oh, darling, why, that's... Why, that's ridiculous!
...اوه، عزيزم، را، اين !آخه را، اين مسخره ست
Yeah. Maybe you fell on your head, Toulouse.
آره. شايد سرت به جايي .خورده، تولوز
Mama, I'm afraid. I wanna go home.
.مامان. من مي ترسم .مي خوام برم خونه
Now, now, my darling, now don't be frightened. You'll see...
...يزي نيست، عزيزم، نترس. حالا مي بيني
Oh, dear. Oh, dear. Now, let's get into the basket, all of us.
اوه، عزيزم. بيايد همي .بريم تو سبد، بيايد
What's gonna happen to us?
ه بلايي سرمون مياد؟
Why, darlings, l, I just don't know.
،را، عزيزم، من .اصلا نمي دونم
It does look hopeless, doesn't it?
انار اميدي نيست، نه؟
I wish we were home with Madame right now.
کاش الان تو خونه .يش مادام بوديم
Oh, poor Madame.
.اوه، مادام بياره
She'll be so worried when she finds us gone.
وقتي ببينه ما نيستيم .خيلي نران ميشه
Duchess? Kittens?
دوشس؟ به ربه ها؟
Oh, my gracious! I had the most horrible dream about them.
اوه، خداي من! ه خواب ترسناکي .درباره شون ديدم
Thank goodness it was only a dream.
خدا رو شکر .که فقط يه خواب بود
Oh, dear, what a terrible night.
،اوه، عزيزم .ه شب ترسناکي
Now, now, my darlings. Don't be frightened.
.خيلي خب، عزيزانم .اصلا نترسيد
The storm will soon pass.
.طوفان به زودي تموم ميشه
Oh! Oh, no! They're gone!
!اوه! اوه، نه !اونا نيستن
Duchess! Kittens!
!دوشس! به ربه ها
Duchess, where are you?
دوشس، کجايي؟
They're gone!
!نيستن
Duchess? Kittens? Gone? Why, that's terrible!
دوشس؟ به ربه ها؟ رفتن؟ !را، خيلي بد شد
But where? Why?
ولي کجا؟ را؟
Good heavens! Anything could happen to them on a night like this!
خداي بزر! تو نين شبي !هر اتفاقي ممکنه براشون بيافته
Get, get washed down a storm drain.
.آب آبذر اونا رو با خودش ببره
Struck by lightning.
.صاعقه بهشون بخوره
Oh, they'll need help.
.اوه، اونا به کمک احتياج دارن
I've just got to find them.
.بايد يداشون کنم
Duchess! Kittens!
!دوشس! به ربه ها
Duchess!
!دوشس
Kittens!
!به ربه ها
I like a chee-chee-chee-chee-rony like they make at home
I like a chee-chee-chee-chee-rony like they make at home
Or a healthy fish with a big backbone
Or a healthy fish with a big backbone
I'm Abraham Delacey
I'm Abraham Delacey
Giuseppe Casey
Giuseppe Casey
Thomas O'Malley
Thomas O'Malley
O'Malley the alley cat
O'Malley the alley cat
I've got that wanderlust
I've got that wanderlust
Gotta walk the scene
Gotta walk the scene
Gotta kick up highway dust
Gotta kick up highway dust
Feel the grass that's green
Feel the grass that's green
Gotta strut them city streets
Gotta strut them city streets
Showin' off my eclat
Showin' off my eclat
Yeah
Yeah
Tellin' my friends of the social elite
Tellin' my friends of the social elite
Or some cute cat I happen to meet
Or some cute cat I happen to meet
That I'm
That I'm
Abraham Delacey Giuseppe Casey
Abraham Delacey Giuseppe Casey
Thomas O'Malley
Thomas O'Malley
O'Malley the alley cat
O'Malley the alley cat
Oh, why, monsieur...
...اوه،موسيو
your name seems to cover all of Europe.
.انار اسمتون به بزري ارواست
Well, of course. I'm the only cat of my kind.
.خب، البته .من تنها نمونه در ونه خودم هستم
I'm king of the highway
I'm king of the highway
Prince of the boulevard
Prince of the boulevard
Duke of the avant-garde
Duke of the avant-garde
The world is my backyard
The world is my backyard
So if you're goin' my way
So if you're goin' my way
That's the road you wanna seek
That's the road you wanna seek
Calcutta to Rome or home sweet home
Calcutta to Rome or home sweet home
In Paris magnifique you all
In Paris magnifique you all
Oh, boy! An alley cat!
!اوه، سر! يه ربه خيابوني
Shh, shh. Listen.
.هيس، هيس. وش کن
I only got myself
I only got myself
And this big old world
And this big old world
But I sip that cup of life
But I sip that cup of life
With my fingers curled
With my fingers curled
I don't worry what road to take
I don't worry what road to take
I don't have to think of that
I don't have to think of that
Whatever I take is the road I make
Whatever I take is the road I make
It's the road of life Make no mistake
It's the road of life Make no mistake
For me
For me
Yeah Abraham Delacey
Yeah Abraham Delacey
Giuseppe Casey Thomas O'Malley
Giuseppe Casey Thomas O'Malley
O'Malley the alley cat
O'Malley the alley cat
That's right And I'm very proud of that
That's right And I'm very proud of that
Yeah
Yeah
Bravo! Very good. You are a great talent.
.براوو! خيلي خوبه .تو استعداد خوبي داري
Well, thank you. And what might your name be?
.خب، متشکرم و اسم شما يه؟
My name is Duchess.
.اسم من دوشس هست
Duchess.
.دوشس
Beautiful. Love it.
.اسم قشنيه .ازش خوشم مياد
And those eyes. Ooh.
.و اون شم ها .اوه
Why, your eyes are like sapphires sparkling so bright.
.بله، شم هات مثل ياقوت درخشانه
They make the morning radiant and light.
شم هات صبح رو .روشن و رنور مي کنند
- How romantic. - Sissy stuff.
.ه رمانتيک - .ه دخترانه -
Oh, c'est tres jolie, monsieur.
.اوه، نهايت لطف شماست، موسيو
Very poetic. But it is not quite Shakespeare.
.خيلي شاعرانه ست .ولي کاملا شکسيري نيست
'Course not. That's pure O'Malley, baby.
.البته که نيست .اين اومالي اصله، عزيزم
Right off the cuff. Yeah. I got a million of'em.
.بالبداهه هستن. آره .ميليون هاي آواز ديه هم بلدم
Oh, no more, please.
.اوه، نه ديه، خواهش ميکنم
I am really in a great deal of trouble.
.الان مشکل بزري برام يش اومده
Trouble?
مشکل؟
Helping beautiful dame... uh, uh, damsels in distress is my specialty.
کمک به خانم...اه، دوشيزه هاي نيازمند کمک .در تخصص منه
Now, what's the hang-up, your ladyship?
خب، حالا مشکلتون يه، خانم؟
Well, it is most important that I get back to Paris.
.خب، من حتما بايد برردم به اريس
So, if you would be just so kind and show me the way.
س، اه ميشه الان لطف کنيد .و راه رو نشون من بدين
Show you the way? Perish the thought!
راه رو نشونت بدم؟ !تو رو خدا دست بردار
We shall fly to Paris on a magic carpet...
ما بايد هلو به هلو ...با يه قاليه رنده
side by side...
...به اريس رواز کنيم
with the stars as our guide...
در حالي که ستاره ها ...راهنمامون هستن
just we two.
.فقط ما دوتا
Oh, that would be wonderful.
.اوه، فوق العاده ميشه
Three? Four?
سه؟ هار نفر؟
Five?
نج تايي؟
Oh, yes, Monsieur O'Malley. These are my children.
.اوه، بله، موسيو اومالي .اينا به هاي من هستن
Oh, how sweet.
.اوه، ه بانمک
Do you really have a magic carpet?
واقعا يه قاليه رنده داري؟
- And are we really gonna ride on it? - Now, now, Marie.
و واقعا مي خوايم باهاش رواز کنيم؟ - .خيلي خب، ماري -
Mama, do I have sparkling sapphire eyes that dazzle, too?
مامان، من هم شم هاي ياقوتي درخشان دارم؟
Ooh, did I say that?
اوه، من اينو فتم؟
Yes, right off your cuff.
.بله، بالبداهه فتي
And you said we're gonna ride on a magic carpet.
و فتي قراره با يه .قاليه رنده رواز کنيم
Well, now, uh, what I meant... You see, l...
...خب، الان، منظورم اينه که ...مي دوني، من
No poetry to cover this situation, Monsieur O'Malley?
آوازي براي فرار از اين وضعيت نداري، آقاي اومالي؟
Well, what I had in mind was a kind of a sports model, baby.
خب، يزي که فتم .يه جور مدل تفريحي بود، عزيزم
- You know, one of those... - Uh, perhaps a, a magic carpet built for two?
...ميدوني، يکي از اون - آه، شايد يه قاليه رنده دو نفره؟ -
I wouldn't take up much room.
.من جاي زيادي رو اشغال نمي کنم
I understand perfectly, Monsieur O'Malley.
،کاملا درکتون مي کنم .آقاي اومالي
Well, come along, darlings.
.خب، بياين بريم، به ها
I'm a tough alley cat, too.
.منم يه ربه خيابوني قوي هستم
Hey, there, you're comin' on. I'll bet you're a real tiger in your neighborhood.
هي، ببينم، بدک نيست. شرط مي بندم .تو شهر خودتون يه لن واقعي هستي
Yeah. That's 'cause I practice all the time.
.آره. آخه هميشه تمرين ميکنم
Now, now, Toulouse, Toulouse, come along, dear.
،خيلي خب، تولوز .تولوز، بيا، عزيزم
Yes, Mama.
.بله، مامان
See ya around, Tiger!
!به اميد ديدار، ببره
Ha-ha. Now, that's quite a family.
.ها-ها. حالا کاملا يه خانواده شدن
And come to think of it, O'Malley, you're not a cat, you're a rat.
،و فکرش رو بکن، اومالي .تو يه ربه نيستي، يه موشي
Right? Right.
.باشه؟ باشه
Hey! Hey, hold up, there!
!هي! هي، صبر کنيد، بررديد
Yes, Monsieur O'Malley?
بله، ،آقاي اومالي؟
Now, look, kids, if I said magic carpet...
،ببينيد، به ها ...اه فتم قاليه رنده
magic carpet it's gonna be.
.س قاليه رنده هست
And it's gonna stop for passengers...
...و براي مسافرها توقف ميکنه
right...
...درست
here.
.همين جا
Oh, boy! We're gonna fly after all.
!اوه، سر .بالاخره رواز مي کنيم
Ah, another flight into the fantasy, Monsieur O'Malley?
آه، يه رواز ديه به فانتزي، موسيو اومالي؟
No, no, no, baby!
!نه، نه، نه، عزيزم
Now, you just hide over there and you leave the rest to J. Thomas O'Malley.
حالا، کافيه اونجا قايم بشيد و بقيه ش .رو بذاريد به عهده جي. توماس اومالي
- Quick, Mama, get in here. - But, but, children...
.بجنب، مامان، بيا اين طرف - ...ولي، ولي، به ها -
Hurry up, Mama. Hurry.
.عجله کن، مامان. بيا
One magic carpet comin' up.
.يه قاليه رنده داره مياد
That's a magic carpet?
اون قاليه رنده هست؟
Stupid cat! Brainless lunatic!
!ربه مسخره !ديوانه بي مخ
All right, step lively. All aboard for Paris.
.خيلي خب، بفرمائيد .به طرف اريس
Why, Mr. O'Malley, you could have lost your life.
آقاي اومالي .ممکن بود جونتون رو از دست بدين
So, I've got a few to spare. Nothin'.
.س ديه زياد ندارم .هيي
How can we ever thank you?
طور مي تونيم ازتون تشکر کنيم؟
My pleasure entirely.
.باعث افتخار من بود
Aloha. Auf Wiedersehen.
.خداحافظ. مي بينمتون
Bon soir. Sayonara.
.خدانهدار. به اميد ديدار
And all those good-bye things, baby.
همه اون يزهاي .خداحافظي، عزيزم
Sayonara, Mister... Oh!
!خداحافظ، آقاي...اوه
- Mama! - Marie! Marie!
!مامان - !ماري! ماري -
- Oh, Marie, are you all right? - Yes, Mama.
اوه، ماري، حالت خوبه؟ - .بله، مامان -
Haven't we met before?
قبلاً همديه رو نديديم؟
Oh, and I'm so very glad we did.
.اوه، و خيلي خوشحالم که همديه رو ديديم
Thank you, Mr. O'Malley, for saving my life.
،متشکرم، آقاي اومالي .که زندي منو نجات دادين
No trouble at all, little princess.
،اصلا قابلي نداشت .شاهزاده کوولو
And when we get to Paris, I'll show you the time of your life.
،و وقتي رسيديم اريس .فرصت زندي رو نشونت ميدم
Oh, I'm so sorry, but...
...اوه، خيلي متأسفم، ولي
Well, we just couldn't.
.خب، ما نمي تونيم
You see, my mistress will be so worried about us.
مي دونيد، بانوي من خيلي .نران ما شده
Well, humans don't really worry too much about their pets.
خب، آدم ها زياد نران حيوانات .خانيشون نميشن
Oh, no. You just don't understand.
.اوه، نه .شما متوجه نيستيد
She loves us very much.
.اون خيلي ما رو دوست داره
Poor Madame, in that big mansion...
،مادام بياره ...تو اون قصر بزر
all alone.
.همه ش تنهاست
In all our days, in tender ways...
،در تمام اون روزها ...با اون که بوديم
her love for us was shown.
.علاقه اون به ما بهمون ثابت شده
And so, you see...
...و مي دونيد
we can't leave her alone.
.نمي تونيم اونو تنها بذاريم و بريم
She'd always say that...
...اون هميشه ميه که
we're the greatest treasure she could own...
ما بزرترين نج هايي هستيم ...که اون مي تونست داشته باشه
because with us she never felt alone.
ون با ما هي وقت .احساس تنهايي نمي کنه
Oh, Roquefort, I've been so worried about you.
،اوه، راکفورت .خيلي نرانت شدم
Did you have any luck at all?
اصلا موفق شدي؟
Not a sign of them, Frou-Frou.
،حتي يه نشونه هم نبود .فرو-فرو
And I've searched all night.
.تمام شب جستجو کردم
I know, and poor Madame didn't sleep a wink either.
مي دونم، مادام بياره هم .شم رو هم نذاشت
Oh, it's a sad day for all of us.
.اوه، براي همه مون روز ناراحت کننده ايه
Morning, Frou-Frou, my pretty steed. Ho-hmm.
،صبح بخير، فرو-فرو .اسب خوشل من. هو-هوم
Can you keep a secret? Hmm? Of course you can.
مي توني يه راز رو يش خودت نه داري؟ .البته که مي توني
I've some news straight from the horse's mouth.
يه خبر برات دارم .که مثل اسب صدا کرده
If you'll pardon the expression, of course. Ha.
البته ببخش از اين اصطلاح استفاده کردم
Look, Frou-Frou, I've made the headlines.
،ببين، فرو-فرو .من تيتر صفحه اول شدم
" Mysterious Catnapper Abducts Family of Cats"
ربه دزد مرموز" "خانواده ربه ها را دزديد
- Well, aren't you proud of me? - So, he's the catnapper!
خب، بهم افتخار نمي کني؟ - !س اون دزد ربه هاست -
The police said it was a professional, masterful job.
ليس فته سرقت حرفه اي .و ماهرانه اي بوده
The work of a genius.
.کار يه نابغه بوده
Not bad, eh, Frou-Frou old girl?
بد نيست، نه، فرو فرو؟
Oh, they won't find a clue to implicate me. Not one single clue.
اوه، اونا يه سرنخ هم براي يدا کردن .من ندارن. حتي يه سرنخ
Why, I'll, I'll, I'll eat my hat if they...
امکان نداره ...سر من کلاه بره
My hat! My umbrella!
!کلاهم !ترم
Oh, oh gracious!
!اوه، خداي من
l, I've got to get those things back tonight.
.بايد امشب اونا رو برردونم
But... Ooh, you...
...اما... اوه، اي
Why, that sneaky, crooked...
...اون آب زيرکاه، کلاه بردار
no good butler of...
...مستخدم بي مصرف
- Anyone for breakfast? - What breakfast? - Where is it?
کسي صبحانه ميل داره؟ - ه صبحانه اي؟ - کجاست؟ -
Right under that magic carpet.
.درست زير اون قاليه جادويي
But now we have to cook up a little spell.
ولي اول بايد .ند تا جادو بکنيم
You know. You ready?
.مي دونيد که آماده ايد؟
All right. First, to make the magic begin...
،خيلي خب، اول ...براي شروع شدن جادو
you wiggle your nose.
.دماغتون رو تکون بديد
And tickle your chin.
.زير انه تون رو بخاريد
Now, you close your eyes...
...حالا، شم هاتون رو ببنديد
and cross your heart.
.و قلبتون رو علامت بزنيد
Then presto! Breakfast a la carte.
!بفرمائيد .صبحانه آماده است
- Hurray! - We did it! - Look, Mama, look.
!عجله کنيد - !موفق شديم - .ببين، مامان، ببين -
Why, Mr. O'Malley, you are amazing!
،اوه، آقاي اومالي !شما فوق العاده هستين
True. True.
.درسته. درسته
Thieves! You robbers! Mangy tramps!
!اي دزدها! غارترها !ولرد هاي بي سر و ا
Take that and that!
!بيريد که اومد، اينم بيريد
Oh! Oh, what a horrible, horrible human.
.اوه! اوه، ه آدم ترسناک بدي
Well, some humans are like that, Duchess.
خب، بعضي آدم ها .اين طوري هستن، دوشس
I've learned to live with it.
.راه و رسم زندي با اونا رو ياد رفتم
I'll show him. Meow!
.نشونش ميدم !ميو
Hey, cool it, you little tiger. That guy's dynamite.
.هي، آروم باش، ببر کوولو .اون يارو خيلي خطرناکه
But he called us tramps.
.ولي اون به ما فت ولرد
Oh, I'll be so glad when we get back home.
اوه، وقتي برسيم خونه .خيلي خوشحال ميشم
Well, that's a long way off so we better get movin'.
خب، راه درازي در يش داريم .س بهتره حرکت کنيم
Gee whiz! Look at that bridge!
!واي !اون ل رو ببين
- Come on, let's play train. - Now, be careful, children.
.بجنب، بيا قطار بازي کنيم - .به ها، مواظب باشيد -
Marie's the caboose. All aboard!
.ماري وان آخريه !مسافران سوار بشيد
- Oh, no! - All right, now, don't panic.
!واي، نه - .خيلي خب، هول نشيد -
Down underneath here.
.بياين اين زير -
Mama!
!مامان
Marie! Oh, Marie!
!ماري! اوه ماري
Keep your head up, Marie. Here I come.
.سرت رو بالا نه دار، ماري .دارم ميام
Thomas! Thomas, up here.
.توماس! توماس، اين بالا
Gee, Marie, why'd you have to fall off the bridge?
ماري، براي ي بايد از ل مي افتادي؟
Thomas! Oh, Thomas! Take care!
!توماس، اوه، توماس !مواظب باش
I'm all right, honey. Don't worry. I'll see ya downstream.
.من خوبم، عزيزم. نران نباش .ايين رودخونه مي بينمتون
What beautiful countryside, Abigail.
.ه منطقه زيبايي، ابييل
Oh, so much like our own dear England.
اوه، خيلي به انليس خودمون .شباهت داره
Oh, indeed yes.
.اوه، درسته
Amelia, if I walk much further, I'll get flat feet.
،آمليا، اه بيشتر راه برم .اهام صاف ميشه
Abigail, we were born with flat feet.
ابييل، ما با اي صاف .به دنيا اومديم
I say, look over there.
.اونجا رو ببين
Oh! Oh, how unusual.
.اوه! اوه، عجيبه
Well, fancy that. A cat learning how to swim.
.فکرش رو بکن .يه ربه شنا کردن ياد بيره
And he's going about it all the wrong way.
و اين کارو .اشتباه انجام بده
Quite. We must correct him.
.کاملا .بايد بهش ياد بديم
Sir! Sir!
!آقا! آقا
You are most fortunate we happened along.
خيلي خوش شانسي که .ما اتفاقي اومديم اينجا
Yes, we're here to help you.
.بله، اومديم کمکت کنيم
No, no. Back off, girls. I'm doin' fine.
.نه، نه، بريد، دخترها .من حالم خوبه
First, you must gain self-confidence by striking out on your own.
اول، بايد با تکيه به خودت .اعتماد به نفس داشته باشي
Go away. I'm tryin' to get to shore.
.بريد .من مي خوام برم به ساحل
You will never learn to swim properly with that willow branch in your mouth.
وقتي اون بوته بيد تو دهانت باشه .ياد نمي يري درست شنا کني
Indeed not!
!درسته ياد نمي يري
Snip, snip. Here we go.
.قيي، قيي .بفرمائيد
Don't do that!
!قطعش نکن
You're doing splendidly!
!کارت عاليه
And don't worry about form. It will come later.
.و نران شکل شنات هم نباش .بعدا درست ميشه
Ooh, he takes to water like a fish, doesn't he?
اوه، مثل ماهي تو آب شنا مي کنه، نه؟
A very enthusiastic pupil.
.شارد مشتاق به اين مين
No. Now, this is no time for fun and games.
نه. الان وقت سررمي .و بازي نيست
Gracious, Amelia. You don't suppose...
.خداي من، آمليا ...فکر نمي کني
Oh, yes! Yes, I do! Bottoms up!
!اوه، بله! اوه، را .دم ها بالا
- Deeper!
!ايين تر -
Look, Ma, there he is.
.مامان، ناه کن، اوناهاش
You really did quite well for a beginner.
به عنوان يه تازه کار .کارت خيلي خوب بود
Oh, Thomas! Thank goodness you're safe.
!اوه، توماس .خدا رو شکر که سالمي
- Keep practicing! - And toodlely pip.
!همين طور تمرين کن - .و خدانهدار -
Can I help you, Mr. O'Malley, huh?
،مي تونم کمکتون کنم آقاي اومالي، ها؟
Help? I've had all the help I can take.
.کمک؟ هر ي کمک بود بهم شده
Oh, mademoiselles, thank you so much for helping Mr. O'Malley.
اوه، خانم ها، خيل متشکرم .که به آقاي اوماللي کمک کردين
Of course, my dear. But first, introductions.
.البته، عزيزم .اما اول، معرفي
Yes. We British like to keep things proper.
بله. ما بريتانيايي ها دوست داريم .همه يز مرتب باشه
Now, now, I am Amelia Gabble, and this is my sister...
،خب، من آمليا بل هستم ...و اينم خواهرم
- Uh, Miss Abigail Gabble. - We're twin sisters.
.آه، دوشيزه ابييل بل - .ما خواهرهاي دوقلو هستيم -
- You might say we're related. - Oh, silly thing.
.شايد فکر کرده باشين با هم نسبتي داريم - .اوه، يز ردنيه -
How nice. I never would have guessed.
.ه خوب .هرز نمي تونستم حدس بزنم
- Look, they got rubber feet. - Yeah!
.ببين، اهاشون لاستيکيه - !آره -
- We're on holiday. - For a walking tour of France.
.تو تعطيلات هستيم - .داريم تو فرانسه ردش مي کنيم -
- Uh, swimming some of the way. - On water, of course.
.آه، البته شنا مي کنيم - .روي آب، البته -
Of course.
.معلومه
Uh, Thomas, this is Amelia and Abigail Gabble.
آه، توماس، اين ها آمليا .و ابييل بل هستن
Yeah, honey. Get those two web-footed lifeguards out of here.
آره، عزيزم. حالا اون نجات غريق هاي .ا رده اي رو دک کن برن
Now, now, Thomas.
.دست بردار، توماس
Okay, okay, baby. Hiya, chicks.
.خيلي خب، عزيزم .سلام، جوجو ها
Oh.
.اوه
We're not chickens. We're geese.
.ما که جوجه نيستيم .ما غاز هستيم
No! I thought you were swans.
.نه بابا! فکر کردم قو هستين
Ooh! Ooh! Flatterer!
!اوه! اوه! اي الوس
Your husband is very charming and very handsome.
شوهرت خيلي جذاب .و خوش هيکله
Well, ha, uh...
...خب، اِه
You see, l-I'm not exactly her husband.
مي دونيد. من دقيقا .شوهرش نيستم
Exactly? You either are or you're not.
.دقيقا؟ يا هستي يا نيستي
All right. I'm not.
.خيلي خب .نيستم
- Oh? - Oh? Hmm.
اوه؟ - .اوه؟ هوم -
- He's scandalous. - He's nothing but a cad.
.افتضاحه - .فقط يه بي تربيته -
- Absolutely. Possibly a reprobate. - A roue.
.حتما. احتمالا بداخلاق هم هست - .فاسده -
- Mmm, his eyes are too close together. - They're shifty, too.
.هوم، شم هاش خيلي به هم نزديکن - .حيله ر هم هستن -
- And look at his crooked smile. - His chin is very weak, too.
.لبخند کجش رو ببين - .انه ش هم خيلي ضعيفه -
Obviously a philanderer who trifles with unsuspecting women's hearts.
ظاهرا يکي از اون لات هاست که .دل زن هاي ساده رو به بازي مي يرن
How romantic.
.ه رمانتيک
Please. Please let me explain.
.خواهش مي کنم .بذارين توضيح بدم
Thomas is a dear friend of ours. He's just helping us to get to...
.توماس يکي از دوستان عزيز ماست ...اون فقط داره کمکمون ميکنه که بريم
Come on, Duchess, come on. Let's get out of here.
.ولشون کن، دوشس .بيا از اينجا بريم
Well, girls, see ya around. We're on our way to Paris.
.خب، دخترها، به اميد ديدار .ما بايد راهمون به اريس رو ادامه بديم
Ooh, how nice. We're going to Paris ourselves.
.اوه، ه جالب .ما هم داريم مي ريم اريس
Why don't you join us?
را به ما ملحق نميشيد؟
I think that's a splendid idea.
.به نظرم فکر خيلي خوبيه
Oh, no.
.اوه، نه
Now, uh, you stand here, dear.
.خب، تو اينجا وايسا، عزيزم
And, uh, let's see, uh, you take this position.
،و بذار ببينم .تو هم بيا اينجا
- Uh, Duchess, you will do nicely here. - Yes, very good.
.آه، دوشس، تو اينجا باشي خوبه - .آره، خيلي خب -
And, and you, dear, you take this place.
،و تو، عزيزم .توهم بيا اينجا
Oh, now that leaves Mr. O'Malley.
.اوه، حالا مي مونه آقاي اومالي
Oh, we can't leave him, can we?
اوه، نمي تونيم اونو جا بذاريم، مه نه؟
Mr. O'Malley, I think you should be the rear end.
آقاي اومالي، به نظرم شما .اون شت باشين خوبه
Ready, everyone? Now, think goose.
همه آماده ايد؟ .حالا، مثل غاز باشين
Forward march.
.قدم رو
Mama, do we have to waddle like they do?
مامان، ما هم بايد مثل اونا کج راه بريم؟
Yes, dear. Think goose.
.بله، عزيزم .مثل غاز باش
When we get to Paris, you must meet Uncle Waldo.
،وقتي رسيديم اريس .بايد عمو والدو رو ببينيد
- Waldo? - Yes, he's our uncle.
والدو؟ - .آره، اون عموي ماست -
We are to meet Uncle Waldo at Le Petit Cafe.
قراره تو کافه له تيت .عمو والدو رو ببينيم
Le Petit Cafe? Oh, that's that famous restaurant.
کافه له تيت؟ اوه، همون .رستوران معروف
Ah! C'est magnifique.
.آه! عاليه
Oh, he bit my finger!
!اوه، انشتم رو از رفت
Get out! Go! Go! Get out! Scram!
!برو بيرون! برو! برو !برو بيرون! برو
Good riddance!
!راحت شديم
Why, why, it's Uncle Waldo!
!واي، عمو والدو
Uncle Waldo!
!عمو والدو
Abigail! Amelia!
!ابييل! آمليا
My two favorite "nooses."
.تله هاي" محبوب من"
Uncle Waldo. Tsk, tsk. l, I do believe you've been drinking.
.عمو والدو .فکر کنم مست شدين
Oh, dear! What happened to your lovely tail feathers?
اوه، عزيزم! ه بلايي سر موهاي دم قشنت اومده؟
Girls, it's outrageous.
.دخترها، ظالمانه ست
Why, you won't believe what they tried to do...
باور نمي کنيد ...مي خواستن ه بلايي سر
to your poor old Uncle Waldo.
.عمو والدوي بياره تون بيارن
Look! Look at this!
!ببين! اينو ببين
" Prime Country Goose A la Provencale.
غاز درجه يک" .روانسي
Stuffed with chestnuts"?
تانده شده با بلوط"؟
"And basted in white wine."
و غلتيده شده" ".در شراب سفيد
Basted? He's been marinated in it.
.غلتيده شده؟ اونو خيس کردن
Dreadful!
!وحشتناکه
Being British, I would have preferred sherry.
،من که بريتانيايي ام .ترجيح ميدم شراب اسانيايي باشه
Sherry! Sherry.
.شراب اسانيايي. اسانيايي
Oh-oh, oh, oh!
!اوه، اوه، اوه، اوه
Oh, Uncle Waldo, you're just too much.
،اوه، عمو والدو .خيلي بامزه اي
You mean, he's had too much.
،منظورت اينه که .خيلي بامزه بود
- Uh, Abigail, Abigail. - Yes, yes.
.آه، ابييل، ابييل - .بله، بله -
We best get Uncle Waldo to bed.
بهتره عمو والدو رو .رو ببريم به تختخواب
Ah, I say there now.
.وايسا ببينم
What's all the whis-whispering about, huh?
دارين يش هم ي   مي کنين؟
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
.هيس، هيس، هيس، هيس
Now, now, now, now, girls. Girls!
.خيلي خب، دخترها !دخترها
Don't shush your old Uncle Waldo.
عمو والدوي يرتون .رو هيس نکنيد
Why, you'll, you'll wake up the whole neighborhood.
آخه، تمام همسايه ها .رو بيدار مي کنين
- Shh. - Whoopee!
.هيس - !هورا -
- No. - Neighborhood.
.نه - .همسايه ها -
- Oh, come along, Uncle Waldo. - Oh, yes, I think we'd better be going.
.اوه، بيا، عمو والدو - .اوه، آره. فکر کنم بهتره بريم -
Oh, right-o, girls.
.اوه، درسته، دخترها
Birds of a feather must "hic" together.
.کبوتر با کبوتر غاز با غاز
That's stick together.
.اون باز هست
I'll say!
!ميم
- Girls! Girls! - Shoo, shoo, shoo.
!دخترها! دخترها - .کيش، کيش، کيش -
You know somethin'? I like Uncle Waldo.
مي دوني يه؟ .از عمو والدو خوشم مياد
Especially when he's marinated.
.مخصوصا وقتي خيس خورده باشه
Frou-Frou, here comes Edgar.
،فرو-فرو .ادار داره مياد
Hurry, Roquefort, hop aboard the motorcycle.
،زودباش، راکفورت .برو سوار موتور سيکلت
And for goodness sakes, do be careful!
!و تو رو خدا مراقب باش
Frou-Frou, tonight operation catnapper will be completed.
فرو-فرو، امشب عمليات .ربه دزدي کامل ميشه
Wish me luck. Fisherman's luck.
.خدا کنه شانس بيارم .شانس ماهييري
Bye, Frou-Frou. Ooh!
.خداحافظ، فرو-فرو !اوه
Lafayette! Lafayette, listen.
!لافيت .لافيت، وش کن
Oh, shucks, Napoleon. That ain't nothing' but a little ol' cricket bug.
اوه، ول کن، نالئون. اون فقط .يه جيرجيرک کوولوي يره
It's squeaky shoes approachin'.
.کفش هاي جيغ جيغوش دارن نزديک ميشن
Oh, cricket bugs don't wear shoes.
اوه، جيرجيرک ها که .کفش نمي وشن
Hush your mouth!
!نيشت رو ببند
Let's see. They're oxford shoes...
.بذار ببينم ...کفش بندي هستن
size nine and a half.
.اندازه نه و نيم
Hole in the left sole, it sounds like.
.انار يه سوراخ تو کفش  هست
- What color are they? - Why, they're black... Ah, now how would I know that?
ه رني هستن؟ - خب سياه... آه، از کجا بدونم؟ -
Hey, now the squeakin' has stopped.
.هي، صداي جيغ جيغ قطع شد
I still say it was a little ol' cricket bug.
من که هنوز ميم .يه جيرجيرک کوولوي يره
I'm the leader.
.من رئيسم
I'll decide what it was.
.من تصميم مييرم اون يه
It was a little ol' cricket bug.
.يه جيرجيرک کوولوي ير بود
I'll see you in the mornin', Napoleon.
.صبح مي بينمت، نالئون
That's my hat! I'm the leader!
!اون کلاه منه !من رئيسم
Well, shoot fire! Don't get sore at me. I ain't done nothin'.
.خب، تير بزن! با من دعوا نکن .من کاري نکردم
Ooh, oh, hey.
.اوه، اوه، هي
Ooh!
!اوه
Mmm, that feels good, Lafayette.
.هوم، خوبه، لافيت
That's all right.
.قابلي نداشت
A little lower and faster there.
يه کم ايين تر .يه کم سريع تر
I'm scratchin' as fast as I can.
.تا اونجايي که مي تونم سريع مالش ميدم
Right there! That's good! Oh, ooh, ooh!
!همين جا! خوبه !اوه، اوه، اوه
Ooh!
!اوه
Mmm, it's so warm and...
...هوم، خيلي رمه و
mmm, cozy.
.هوم، راحت
Wh-Wh-What's goin' on? Lafayette, what in tar nation are you tryin' to do?
ي خبر شده؟ لافيت، ه غلطي مي خواي بکني؟
Aw, I get blamed for everything.
هر ي ميشه .به من ير ميدي
Wait a minute! Where's my hat? Where...
!صبر کن ببينم ...کلاه من کجاست؟ کجا
And somebody stole my bumbershoot.
.و يه نفر تر منو دزديده
Well, where's my beddie-bye basket?
سبد خواب من کجاست؟
And whoever it is, is gonna get it and get it good.
،و هر کي باشه .مي يرمش، خوبم مي يرمش
This time, I get the tender part.
،اين دفعه .قسمت حساس با منه
Hush your mouth! Now, come on.
!نيشت رو ببند .حالا، بيا
Hey, N-Napoleon, oh, it's them shoes again!
،هي، نالئون !اوه، بازم کفش هاي اونه
Yeah, yeah, I hear' em.
.آره، آره، مي شنوم
Napoleon, I'm plumb goose-pimply scared.
.نالئون، من خيلي مي ترسم
Now, this is no time to turn chicken.
.حالا وقت جوجه بازي نيست
I got a feelin' this case is gonna bust wide open.
حس ميکنم اين مورد .مي خواد حمله کنه
Ah, d-d-d-did, did, did, did you see him?
آه، ـ ـ ـ يزي ديدي؟
No, no. He sneaked up behind me and tailgated me.
نه، نه. دزدکي اومد شتم .و منو زد
- Well, he didn't hurt me. He hit me on the head. - Shh, shh.
.خب، به من صدمه نزد. زد به سرم - .هيس، هيس -
Listen.
.وش کن
Sounds like a one-wheeled, oh...
...انار صداي يک رخه
- A one-wheeled what? - You're not gonna believe this...
يه ي يه رخ؟ - ...باورت نميشه -
but it's a one-wheeled haystack.
.ولي يه کومه علف يک رخه
Hey! There it goes! Come on, after it!
!هي، اوناهاش !بجنب، بريم دنبالش
- I got him, I got him, I got him! - Ouch! That's me!
!رفتمش، رفتمش، رفتمش - !آخ! اين منم -
Oh, wow.
.اوه، واي
Oh, get him, get him, get him, get him!
،اوه، بيرش، بيرش !بيرش، بيرش
Well, c'est la guerre, Napoleon. I guess you can't win 'em all.
.خب، نميشه کاريش کرد، نالئون .انار اصلا نمي توني شکستش بدي
Ow! Ohh, ohh, ohh! Criminently!
!آخ! اوه، اوه، اوه !خداي من
Thomas, Madame will be so worried. Are you sure we can't get home tonight?
.توماس، مادام خيلي نران ميشه مطمئني امشب نمي رسيم خونه؟
Mama, I'm tired.
.مامان، من خسته ام
Me, too! And my feet hurt.
!منم همين طور .و ام درد ميکنه
Look, baby, it's late, and the kids are bushed.
،ببين، عزيزم، ديروقته .و به ها خسته ان
I'll bet we walked a hundred miles!
شرط مي بندم !صد مايل راه رفتيم
I'll bet it's more than a thousand!
!بيشتر از هزار تاست
Now, now, darlings, cheer up.
،خيلي خب، عزيزانم .خوشحال باشين
Mr. O'Malley knows a place where we can stay tonight.
آقاي اومالي يه جا رو مي شناسه .که مي تونيم امشب رو اونجا بمونيم
How much farther is it, Mr. O'Malley?
آقاي اومالي، قدر دوره؟
Keep your whiskers up, tiger. It's just beyond that next chimney pot.
.سبيل هات رو بالا نه دار، ببره .درست شت اون کلاهک دودکشه
Well, there it is. My own penthouse pad.
.خب، رسيديم .هارطاقي تخت و نرم من
It's not exactly the Ritz, but it's peaceful and quiet. And you'll...
،زياد باشکوه نيست ...اما ساکت و آرومه. و شما
Oh! Oh, no!
!اوه! اوه، نه
Sounds like Scat Cat and his gang have dropped by.
انار اسکات ربه و دار و دسته ش .يه سري زدن
Oh, friends of yours?
اوه، دوستانت هستن؟
Uh-huh, yeah. They're old buddies. And they're, they're real swingers.
.آها، آره. رفيق هاي قديمي . و اونا، واقعا ولرد هستن
Swingers? What is a swinger?
ولرد؟ ولرد ديه يه؟
You know, uh, not exactly your type, Duchess.
،مي دوني، اِه .اصلا مثل شما نيستن، دوشس
And, uh, maybe we'd better find another place. Huh?
اِه، اه مي خواي يه جاي بهتري يدا کنيم. ها؟
Oh, no, no, no. I would like to see your pad, and meet your Scat Cat.
اوه، نه، نه، نه. دلم مي خواد .تختت و اسکات ربه رو ببينم
Well, okay.
.خب، باشه
Hey, Scat Cat, blow some of that sweet stuff my way.
هي، ربه اسکات، يه کم .از اون آوازهات رو براي ما بخون
Well, lookie here! Big Man O'Malley is back in his alley.
!خب، اينجا رو ببين .اومالي بزر برشته به خيابون خودش
Swing on down here, daddy!
!بيا اين ايين، بابا
Lay some skin on me, Scat Cat. Yeah!
.بزن قدش ببينم، اسکات ربه !آره
Welcome home, O'Malley.
.به خونه خوش اومدي، اومالي
Duchess, this is the greatest cat of'em all.
دوشس، اين بهترين ربه .بين همه ايناست
Oh, I'm delighted to meet you, Monsieur Scats Cat.
،اوه، از ديدار با شما خوشوقتم .موسيو اسکات ربه
Likewise, Duchess.
.همنين، دوشس
You're too much.
.شما خيلي بامزه ايد
Oh, ho-ho, you are charming.
،اوه، هو-هو .شما فوق العاده ايد
And your music is so...
...و موسيقي تون خيلي
so different, ah, so exciting.
،خيلي متفاوت .آه، و مهيج هست
It isn't Beethoven, Mama, but it sure bounces.
،بتهوون نيست، مامان .ولي مطمئنا حال ميده
Say! This kitten cat knows where it's at.
ببين! اين به ربه .ميدونه ي يه
- Knows where what's at? - Well, little lady, let me elucidate here.
ميدوني ي يه؟ - .خب، خانم جوان، بذار توضيح بدم -
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
Because a cat's the only cat who knows where it's at
Because a cat's the only cat who knows where it's at
Tell me, everybody's pickin'up on that feline beat
Tell me, everybody's pickin'up on that feline beat
- 'Cause everything else is obsolete - Strictly high-button shoes
- 'Cause everything else is obsolete - Strictly high-button shoes
A square with a horn makes you wish you weren't born
A square with a horn makes you wish you weren't born
Every time he plays
Every time he plays
But with a square in the act you can set music back
But with a square in the act you can set music back
To the caveman days
To the caveman days
I've heard some corny birds who tried to sing
I've heard some corny birds who tried to sing
But still a cat's the only cat who knows how to swing
But still a cat's the only cat who knows how to swing
Who wants to dig a longhaired gig and stuff like that
Who wants to dig a longhaired gig and stuff like that
When everybody wants to be a cat
When everybody wants to be a cat
A square with a horn makes you wish you weren't born
A square with a horn makes you wish you weren't born
Every time he plays
Every time he plays
Oh, a rinky, tinky, dinky
Oh, a rinky, tinky, dinky
With a square in the act you can set music back
With a square in the act you can set music back
To the caveman days
To the caveman days
Oh, a rinky, tinky, tinky
Oh, a rinky, tinky, tinky
Yes, everybody wants to be a cat
Yes, everybody wants to be a cat
Because a cat's the only cat who knows where it's at
Because a cat's the only cat who knows where it's at
When playing jazz you always has a welcome mat
When playing jazz you always has a welcome mat
'Cause everybody digs a swingin' cat
'Cause everybody digs a swingin' cat
Oh, boy, fellas, let's rock the joint!
Oh, boy, fellas, let's rock the joint!
Groove it, cats.
.عاليه، ربه ها
Shanghai, Hong Kong egg fu yung
Shanghai, Hong Kong egg fu yung
Fortune cookie always wrong
Fortune cookie always wrong
That's a hot one!
!اين يکي باحال بود
How about you and me, Duchess?
من و تو طور، دوشس؟
Yes, let's swing it, Thomas.
.آره، بزن بريم، توماس
Groovy, Mama, groovy!
!خوبه، مامان، خوبه
Blow it, small fry, blow it.
.فوت کن، کوولو، فوت کن
Boy, he blew it!
!سر، اون فوت کرد
But he was-a close!
!ولي اون بسته بود
- Mmm! - Beautiful!
!هوم - !زيباست -
If you want to turn me on
If you want to turn me on
Play your horn Don't spare the tone
Play your horn Don't spare the tone
And blow a little soul
And blow a little soul
Into the tune
Into the tune
Let's take it to another key
Let's take it to another key
Modulate and wait for me
Modulate and wait for me
I'll take a few ad-libs and pretty soon
I'll take a few ad-libs and pretty soon
The other cats will all commence
The other cats will all commence
Congregatin' on the fence
Congregatin' on the fence
Beneath the alley's only light
Beneath the alley's only light
Where every note is
Where every note is
Out of sight
Out of sight
Everybody, everybody
Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
Hallelujah Everybody, everybody
Hallelujah Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
I'm tellin' you Everybody, everybody
I'm tellin' you Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
- Yeah - Everybody, everybody
- Yeah - Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
- Mmm - Everybody, everybody
- Mmm - Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
- Hallelujah - Everybody, everybody
- Hallelujah - Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
Because a cat's the only cat
Because a cat's the only cat
Who knows where it's at
Who knows where it's at
Oh, yeah
Oh, yeah
Happy dreams, my loves.
.خواب هاي خوب ببينين، به ها
I'll bet they're on that magic carpet right now.
شرط مي بندم همين الان روي اون .قاليه رنده هستن
They could hardly keep their eyes open.
به سختي مي تونستن .شم هاشون رو باز نه دارن
Oh! Such an exciting day.
.اوه! ه روز دلذيري
It sure was. And what a finale!
.مطمئنا بود !و ه اياني داشت
Thomas, your friends are really delightful.
توماس، دوستانت .واقعا خوش هستن
I just love them.
.ازشون خوشم اومد
Well, they're kind a rough, you know, around the edges.
،خب، مي دوني، بعضي وقت ها .يه جورايي لوطي هستن
But if you're ever in a jam, wham, they're right there.
،ولي اه مشکلي داشته باشي .بوم، يداشون ميشه
And, wham, when we needed you...
،و، بوم ...وقتي بهت احتياج داشتن
you were right there.
.درست همون جايي
Hmm, that was just a lucky break for me, baby.
هوم، اين براي من فقط .يه استراحت شانسي بود، عزيزم
Oh, and thank you so much for offering us your home.
اوه، و خيلي ممنونم .که ما رو به خونه ت آوردي
Oh, I mean your pad.
.اوه منظورم تختته
- It's very nice. - Well now, wait a minute.
.جاي خيلي خوبيه - .صبر کن ببينم -
You know, this is the low-rent district, remember?
مي دوني، اين منطقه فقيرنشينه، يادته؟
No, no, no, I like it!
!نه، نه، نه، دوستش داشتم
Well, uh, well, all it needs is a, is a little tidying up.
خب، اِه، خب فقط يه کم .تميزکاري لازم داره
And, well, maybe a, a little feminine touch.
و خب، شايد يه کم .دستکاري هاي زنانه
Well, if you're applying for the job, well...
باشه، اه بخواي اين کارو ...بکني، خب
Goody! Mother's going to work for Mr. O'Malley.
ه خوب! مادر مي خواد .براي آقاي اومالي کار کنه
Boy! Your eyes are like sapphires.
.سر! شم هات مثل ياقوته
Gee! Ha. That's pretty corny, though, huh?
واي! البته اين حرف رنده، نه؟
Oh, no! Not at all.
.اوه، نه! اصلا
Any woman would like it.
.هر زني ازش خوشش مياد
l, I mean, even little Marie.
.يعني، مثلا، ماري کوولو
Yeah. All those little kittens, Duchess, I love 'em.
،آره، همه اون به ربه هاي کوولو .دوشس، عاشقشون هستم
And they are very fond of you.
.اونا هم باهات انس رفتن
- Yeah! - Well, you know, - Shh. - they need a...
!آره - ...خب، ميدوني، اونا به يه -
Well, you know, a sort...
...خب، ميدوني، اونا يه جورايي
Well, a sort of a... Well, a father around.
...راستش، يه جورايي .يه جورايي به در نياز دارن
Oh, Thomas, Thomas, that would be wonderful!
،اوه، توماس، توماس !فوق العاده ميشه
Oh, darling, if, if only I could.
،اوه، عزيزم .فقط، اه مي تونستم
- But why can't ya? - Because of Madame.
ولي را نمي توني؟ - .به خاطر مادام -
l, I could never leave her.
.هرز نمي تونم ترکش کنم
But, but Madame's...
...ولي، ولي مادام يه
well, she's just another human.
.خب، اون يه انسانه
You're just her house pets.
.شما فقط حيوانات خاني اون هستيد
Oh, no, no! We mean far more to her than that!
اوه، نه، نه! ما براي اون !بيشتر از اين يزا هستيم
Oh, I'm sorry, my dear...
...اوه، متأسفم، عزيزم
but we just have to go home tomorrow.
.ولي مجبوريم فردا بريم خونه
Yeah.
.آره
Well, I guess you know best.
.خب، به نظرم هر طور مايلي
But I'm gonna miss you, baby.
.ولي دلم برات تن ميشه، عزيزم
And those kids!
!و اون به ها
Gee, I'm gonna miss them, too.
واي، دلم براي اونا .هم تن ميشه
- Well, we almost had a father. - Yeah.
.خب، تقريبا يه در داشتيم - .آره -
Let's go back to bed.
.بياين بررديم به تختخواب
Good night, Duchess.
.شب بخير، دوشس
Good night, Thomas.
.شب به خير، توماس
Hey! Meow!
!هي! ميو
What a classy neighborhood!
!ه محله باکلاسي
- Dig these fancy wigwams. - Wigwams?
.اين خيمه هاي خيالي رو - خيمه؟ -
Are you sure we're on the right street?
مطمني تو خيابون درستي هستيم؟
Yes. Yes. Let's hurry. We're almost home.
.آره. آره. عجله کن .ديه تقريبا رسيديم
Duchess! Kittens! Hallelujah, they're back!
!دوشس! به ربه ها !خدا رو شکر، اونا برشتن
Oh, no! Edgar! I've got to do something quick!
!اوه، نه! ادار !بايد فورا يه کاري بکنم
Edgar, old chap, get used to the finer things of life.
ادار، مرد ير، عادت کردي .يه يزهاي بهتر زندي
Ooh, someday they're all going to be yours, you sly old fox.
اوه، يه روز همه اين يزا .مال تو ميشه، اي روباه مکار ير
Oh! Oh, he got me!
!اوه !اوه، منو زد
- Hurray, we're home! - Wait for me, wait for me!
!عجله کنيد، رسيديم خونه - !صبر کن منم بيام، صبر کن -
Me first! Me first!
!اول من! اول من
It's locked.
.قفله
Come on! Let's all start meowing.
!بجنب .بياين ميو ميو کنيم
It can't be them! The kittens!
!امکان نداره خودشون باشن !به ربه ها
Don't come in!
!نيايد تو
Go away! Away!
!از اينجا بريد! بريد
Look! There's Roquefort.
.ببين! راکفورت اونجاست
- Hi, Roquefort. - He's sure glad to see us.
.سلام، راکفورت - .حتما از ديدن ما خوشحال شده -
I don't know what to say.
.نمي دونم ي بم
I only wish that l...
...اي کاش مي تونستم
Maybe just a...
...شايد يه
short, sweet good-bye would be easiest.
يه خداحافظي کوتاه و خوب .آسون تر باشه
I'll never forget you, Thomas O'Malley.
،هرز فراموشت نمي کنم .توماس اومالي
- Bye. - So long, baby.
.خدانهدار - .خداحافظ، عزيزم -
Don't come in! Look out for Edgar!
!نيايد تو !مواظب ادار باشيد
Duchess, wherever have you been?
دوشس، کجا بودي؟
Look out for the...
...مواظب
sack.
.کيسه باشين
Well...
...خب
I guess they won't need me anymore.
فکر کنم ديه به من .احتياجي ندارن
You came back!
!برشتين
Oh, it, it just isn't fair.
.اوه، اين عادلانه نيست
Edgar! Edgar, come quickly!
!ادار! ادار، فورا بيا
Coming, Madame, coming!
!اومدم، مادام، اومدم
I'll take care of you later.
.بعدا حسابتون رو مي رسم
Oh, Edgar, they're back! I heard them!
!اوه، ادار، اونا برشتن !صداشون رو شنيدم
Hurry, hurry, let them in.
.بجنب، بجنب، در رو روشون باز کن
Duchess? Kittens?
دوشس؟ به ربه ها؟
Come here, my darlings. Where are you? Come on.
.بياين، عزيزانم .کجايين؟ بياين
Uh, allow me, Madame.
.آه، اجازه بديد، مادام
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
،بياين، يشي، يشي، يشي ،يشي، يشي، يشي
kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
،يشي، يشي، يشي، يشي
His name is "O"' what?
اسمش "او" يه؟
His name is O'Malley. O'Malley.
.اسمش اومالي هست .اومالي
Abraham Delacey Guiseppe Casey.
ابراهيم دلاسي .جوس کيسي
Oh, never, never mind. Just run, move, go get him!
.اوه، ولش کن !فقط بدو، برو بيارش
Yes, yes, I'm on my way!
!آره، آره، دارم ميرم
I told you it was Edgar.
.فتم که ادار بود
Aw, shut up, Toulouse.
.خفه شو، تولوز
Oh, it's no use, Edgar.
.اوه، بي فايده است، ادار
I'm afraid it was just the imagination of an old lady.
متأسفانه اين فقط تخيلات .يه يرزن بود
But I was so sure that I heard them.
ولي کاملا مطمئن بودم .صداشون رو شنيدم
I'm so sorry, Madame.
.خيلي متأسفم، مادام
Mr. O'Malley!
!آقاي اومالي
Hey, stop!
!هي، وايسا
Duchess, kittens in trouble. Butler did it.
.دوشس، به ربه ها تو دردسر افتادن .کار يشخدمت بود
Duchess and kittens in trouble?
دوشس و به ها تو دردسر افتادن؟
Look, you go get Scat Cat and his gang of alley cats.
ببين، تو برو اسکات ربه و روه .ربه هاي خيابوني رو خبر کن
A-Alley cats? But I'm a mouse!
ربه هاي خيابوني؟ !ولي من يه موشم
- Look, I'm gonna need help. - You mean you want me...
.ببين، من کمک لازم دارم - ...يعني مي خواي من -
Move! Just tell 'em O'Malley sent you, and you won't have a bit of trouble.
،برو! فقط بو اومالي تو رو فرستاده .تا مشکلي برات يش نياد
" No trouble," he said.
."اون فت "هي مشکلي
Well, that's easy for, ah, for what's-his-name to say.
،خب، فتنش براي ، اِه .اون اسمشو يادم نيست آسونه
He's got nine lives. I've only got one.
.اون نُه تا جون داره .من فقط يه جون دارم
What's a little swinger like you doin' on our side of town?
يه ولرد کوولو مثل تو تو منطقه ما يکار مي کنه؟
Oh, please, ah, I was sent here for help by a cat.
اوه، خواهش مي کنم، يه ربه .منو فرستاده براي کمک
Why, this is outrageous! This is crazy!
!ي، اين مسخره است !ديوانيه
Kinky!
!عجيبه
Oh, but, but honest! He told me just to mention his name.
!اوه، ولي راست ميم .اون فت اسمش رو به شما بم
So, start mentioning name, rodent!
!س، اسمش رو بو، موش کوولو
Now... Oh, now, wait a minute, fellows.
.خب... اوه، يه دقيقه صبر کنين، رفقا
Lo... Don... Look, don't, don't, don't, don't rush me. His name is O'Toole.
.لو...نکنيد... ببين، منو نخوريد .اسمش اوتولي بود
I don't dig him. Strike one.
.اسمشو به خاطر ندارم .شانس اول
Oh, ooh, O'Brien!
!اوه، اوه، اوبراين
- Strike two. - Oh, boy.
.شانس دوم - .اوه، سر -
- You believe me, don't you? - Keep talkin', mousey.
شما حرفمو باور مي کنيد، نه؟ - .ادامه بده، موشي -
H-How about O'Grady?
اوريدي طور؟
Huh?
ها؟
Mousey, you just struck out. Any last words?
.موشي، شانست تموم شد حرف آخري نداري؟
Oh, no, oh! Why did I listen to that O'Malley cat?
اوه، اوه! را به حرف اون ربه اومالي وش کردم؟
- O'Malley?
اومالي؟ -
Hold it, cats. This little guy is on the level.
.صبر کنين، به ها .اين کوولو راست ميه
You're darn tootin' I'm on the level!
!حالا فهميدين من راست ميم
Oh, we didn't mean-a to, to rough-a you, squeaky.
اوه، نمي خواستيم اذيتت .کنيم، جيغ جيغو
Don't worry about me. O'Malley needs help.
.نران من نباشين .اومالي کمک لازم داره
Duchess and the kittens are in trouble.
دوشس و به ربه ها .در خطرن
Come on, cats. We gotta split.
.بجنبين، ربه ها .بايد جدا بشيم
Hey, wait for me! You don't know the way!
!هي، صبر کنين منم بيام !شما راه رو بلد نيستين
Now, my little pesky pets, you're going to travel first-class...
،خب، ربه هاي مزاحم کوولو ...يه مسافرت درجه يک
in your own private compartment...
...تو کوه اختصاصي تون
all the way to Timbuktu.
.(تا تيمباکتو (مالي
And this time, you'll never come back.
،و اين دفعه .هرز برنمي رديد
Oh, oh, oh, we-we-we've got to hurry.
،اوه، اوه، اوه .بايد عجله کنيم
The baggage truck will be here any moment now.
ماشين حمل وسايل .هر لحظه ممکنه برسه
Ooh!
!اوه
Over there! They're in the trunk!
!اونجا !تو صندوق هستن
Quiet!
!ساکت
Everybody out of here fast.
.فورا از اينجا برين بيرون
You're going to Timbuktu...
...شما بايد برين به تيمباکتو
if it's the last thing I do.
.حتي آخر عمرم جون تو
Well, Mac, this must be the trunk, eh?
خب، مک، اين بايد صندوقه باشه، نه؟
Yup! And she goes all the way to Timbuktu.
آره! و يه راست ميره .به تيمباکتو
Heave ho!
!بزن بره
Now, my pets, a little closer together.
،خب، حيوانات من .يه کم به هم نزديکتر بشيد
Good! Good!
!خوبه! خوبه
Look, Georges, what do you think?
،ببين، جرج نظرت يه؟
Very good, very good!
!خيلي خوبه، خيلي خوبه
But I think we should get on with the will.
ولي فکر کنم بايد .بريم سراغ وصيت نامه
Yes, yes, of course. But you know what to do.
.آره، آره، البته .اما تو که مي دوني يکار بايد بکني
Very well. Scratch one butler.
.خيلي خب .يشخدمت خط خورده ميشه
You know, Georges, if Edgar had only known about the will...
مي دوني، جرج، اه ادار ...يزي از وصيت نامه مي دونست
I'm sure he never would have left.
.مطمئنم هرز از اينجا نمي رفت
Duchess, it's wonderful to have you all back.
.دوشس، خوشحالم همه تون برشتيد
And I think this young man is very handsome.
و به نظرم اين مرد جوان .خيلي خوش قيافه است
Shall we keep him in the family?
بايد تو خانواده نهش داريم؟
Of course we will.
.البته که نهش مي داريم
We need a man around the house.
تو خونه به يه مرد .احتياج داريم
An-and, Georges, we must be sure to provide for their future little ones.
و جرج، بايد مطمئن بشيم که .خرج به هاي آينده شون هم بمونه
Of course! The more the merrier.
!البته .هر ي بيشتر بهتر
Now, don't move. Smile.
.حالا، تکون نخوريد .لبخند بزنيد
Say cheese!
!بيد نير
Did somebody say "cheese"?
کسي فت "نير"؟
Thank you.
.متشکرم
Now, run along downstairs. There's a surprise for you.
.حالا، بريد طبقه ايين .مي خوام غافليرتون کنم
Adelaide, what's that music?
،آدلايد اون موسيقي يه؟
Sounds like a gang of swinging hep cats.
مثل صداي يه روه .ربه رقاصه
That's exactly what they are, Georges.
.دقيقا همين هستن، جرج
They're the start of my new foundation.
.اونا آغاز موسسه جديد من هستن
What foundation?
ه موسسه اي؟
My home for all the alley cats of Paris.
خونه من براي تمام .ربه هاي خيابوني اريس
Everybody, everybody
Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody wants to be a cat
Everybody, whoopee
Everybody, whoopee
Everybody, everybody
Everybody, everybody
Everybody wants to be
Everybody wants to be
A cat
A cat
Hey, Napoleon, that sounds like the end.
،هي، نالئون .انار ايان داستانه
Wait a minute. I'm the leader.
.صبر کن ببينم .من رئيسم
I'll say when it's the end.
.من ميم ه زماني ايانه
It's the end.
.الان ايانه
Oh, yeah
.اوه، بله